Guide to the Victorian Politicians: Photograph Album, ca. 1860
Department of Special Collections
Victorian politicians: photograph album,
ca. 1860
MSS PHOTO 190
1 album (47 cartes-de-visite.)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Collection contains 47 cartes de visite from 39 prominent British politicians from the Victorian era. Signature on cover, James E. Healey.
Administrative Information
Access
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1997.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Collection contains 47 cartes de visite from 39 prominent British politicians from the Victorian era. Signature on cover, James E. Healey.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Beresford Hope, A.J.B. (Alexander James Beresford), 1820-1887.; Plimsoll, Samuel.; Whalley, G.H. (George Hammond), 1813-1878.; Cranbrook, Gathorne Gathorne-Hardy, Earl of, 1814-1906.; Cardwell, Edward.; Forster, W.E. (William Edward),$f1818-1886.; Iddesleigh, Stafford Henry Northcote, Earl of, 1818-1887.; Brougham and Vaux, Henry Brougham, Baron, 1778-1868.; Hughes, Tom.; Lowe, Robert.; Buckingham and Chandos, Richard Temple Nugent Brydges Chandos,.; Bright, Jacob.; Bruce, Henry A.; Miall, Edward.; Derby, Edward Henry Stanley, Earl of, 1826-1893.; Cairns, Hugh McCalmont, Sir.; Granville, 2nd Earl of.; Gladstone, W.E. (William Ewart), 1809-1895.; Graham, James.; Argyll, George Douglas Campbell, Duke of, 1823-1900.; Derby, 14th Earl of.; Bright, 1811-1889.; Cobden, Richard.; Chevalier, Michel, 1806-1879.; Lyndhurst, John Singleton Copley, Baron, 1772-1863.; Dilke, Charles Wentworth, Sir, 1843-1911.; Russell, John, Lord.; Cross, Richard Assheton, 1823-1914.; Palmerston, Henry John Temple, Viscount, 1784-1865.; Amberely, Lord.; Grove, Thomas N.A.; Brand, Henry B.W., Sir.; Villiers, Charles Pelham, 1802-1898.; Fawcett, Henry, 1833-1884.; Lewis, George Cornwall, Sir.; Disraeli, Benjamin, Earl of Beaconsfield, 1804-1881.; Palmerston, Lord.; Peel, Robert, Sir, Jr.; Grey, Henry George Grey, Earl, 1802-1894.; Photography--History.; Great Britain--History--19th century.; Great Britain--Politics and government--19th century.; Albums.; Carte de visite photographs.; Photoprints.; Healey, James E.
Collection Contents
- Beresford Hope, A.J.B. (Alexander James Beresford), 1820-1887, Card no. 1
- Plimsoll, Samuel, Card no. 2
- Whalley, G.H. (George Hammond), 1813-1878, Card no. 3
- Cranbrook, Gathorne Gathorne-Hardy, Earl of, 1814-1906, Card no. 4
- Cardwell, Edward. later 1st Viscount Cardwell, Card no. 5
- Forster, W.E. (William Edward), 1818 - 1886, Card no. 6
- Iddesleigh, Stafford Henry Northcote, Earl of, 1818 - 1887, Card no. 7
- Brougham and Vaux, Henry Brougham, Baron, 1778 - 1868, Card no. 8
- Brougham and Vaux, Henry Brougham, Baron, 1778 - 1868, Card no. 9
- Hughes, Tom, Card no. 10
- Lowe, Robert. later 1st Viscount Sherwood, Card no. 11
- Buckingham and Chandos, Richard Temple Nugent Brydges Chandos, Duke of, 1776-1839., Card no. 12
- Bright, Jacob.., Card no. 13
- Bruce, Henry A., Card no. 14
- Miall, Edward., Card no. 15
- Derby, Edward Henry Stanley, Earl of, 1826-1893, Card no. 16
- Derby, Edward Henry Stanley, Earl of, 1826-1893, Card no. 17
- Cairns, Hugh McCalmont, Sir., Card no. 18
- Granville, 2nd Earl of., Card no. 19
- Gladstone, W.E. (William Ewart), 1809-1895, Card no. 20
- Gladstone, W.E. (William Ewart), 1809-1895, Card no. 21
- Graham, James., Card no. 22
- Argyll, George Douglas Campbell, Duke of, 1823-1900, Card no. 23
- Derby, 14th Earl of., Card no. 24
- Derby, 14th Earl of., Card no. 25
- Bright, John, 1811-1889, Card no. 26
- Bright, John, 1811-1889, Card no. 27
- Cobden, Richard., Card no. 28
- Chevalier, Michel, 1806-1879, Card no. 29
- Lyndhurst, John Singleton Copley, Baron, 1772-1863, Card no. 30
- Dilke, Charles Wentworth, Sir, 1843-1911, Card no. 31
- Russell, John, Lord., Card no. 32
- Russell, John, Lord., Card no. 33
- Cross, Richard Assheton, 1823-1914, Card no. 34
- Palmerston, Henry John Temple, Viscount, 1784-1865, Card no. 35
- Amberely, Lord, Card no. 36
- Grove, Thomas N.A., Card no. 37
- Brand, Henry B.W., Sir., Card no. 38
- Villiers, Charles Pelham, 1802-1898, Card no. 39
- Fawcett, Henry, 1833-1884., Card no. 40
- Lewis, George Cornwall, Sir., Card no. 41
- Disraeli, Benjamin, Earl of Beaconsfield, 1804-1881, Card no. 42
- Disraeli, Benjamin, Earl of Beaconsfield, 1804-1881, Card no. 43
- Palmerston, Lord., Card no. 44
- Brougham and Vaux, Henry Brougham, Baron, 1778-1868, Card no. 45
- Peel, Robert, Sir, Jr., Card no. 46
- Grey, Henry George Grey, Earl, 1802-1894, Card no. 47